[
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"\"Now is the winter of our discontent\" is a line from which Shakespearian play?", "answer":0,"answers":["Richard III", "Romeo and Juliet", "Macbeth"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"\"Our Town\" is a play by whom?", "answer":0,"answers":["Thornton Wilder"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"\"The Diary of Anne Frank\" was first published in English under what title?", "answer":0,"answers":["The diary of a young girl"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A band of painted or sculpted decoration, often at the top of a wall.", "answer":0,"answers":["A frieze"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A composition made of cut and pasted pieces of materials, sometimes with images added by the artist.", "answer":0,"answers":["Collage"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A decorative art movement that emerged in the late nineteenth century. Characterized by dense assymmetrical ornamentation in sinuous forms, it is often symbolic and of an erotic nature.", "answer":0,"answers":["Art nouveau"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A design style prevalent during the 1920s and 1930s, characterized by a sleek use of straight lines and slender forms.", "answer":0,"answers":["Art deco"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A European movement beginning in France in the thirteenth century. The artworks are characterized by a linear, graceful, elegant style more naturalistic than that which had existed previously in Europe.", "answer":0,"answers":["Gothic", "Renaissance", "Romanesque"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A European movement of the late eighteenth to mid-nineteenth century. In reaction to neoclassicism, it focused on emotion over reason, and on spontaneous expression.", "answer":0,"answers":["Romanticism", "Gothic", "Romanesque"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A European style developed in France in the late eleventh century. Its sculpture is ornamental, stylized and complex.", "answer":0,"answers":["Romanesque", "Gothic", "Neoclassicism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A European style of the late eighteenth and early nineteenth centuries. Its elegant, balanced works revived the order and harmony of ancient Greek and Roman art.", "answer":0,"answers":["Neoclassicism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A figurative movement that emerged in the United States and Britain in the late 1960s and 1970s. The subject matter, usually everyday scenes, is portrayed in an extremely detailed, exacting style. It is also called _superrealism_, especially when referring to sculpture.", "answer":0,"answers":["Photorealism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A flat board used by a painter to mix and hold colors, traditionally oblong, with a hole for the thumb.", "answer":0,"answers":["Palette"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A group of American painters who united out of opposition to academic standards in the early twentieth century.", "answer":0,"answers":["The eight"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A group of English painters formed in 1848. These artists attempted to recapture the style of painting preceding Raphael. They rejected industrialized England and focused on painting from nature, producing detailed, colorful works.", "answer":0,"answers":["Pre-Raphaelite Brotherhood"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A large painting or decoration done on a wall.", "answer":0,"answers":["Mural"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A late-nineteenth-century French school of painting. It focused on transitory visual impressions, often painted directly from nature, with an emphasis on the changing effects of light and color.", "answer":0,"answers":["Impressionism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A method of painting developed by Seurat and Signac in the 1880s. It used dabs of pure color that were intended to mix in the eyes of viewers rather than on the canvas. It is also called _divisionism_ or _neoimpressionism_.", "answer":0,"answers":["Pointillism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A method of producing images or letters from sheets of cardboard, metal, or other materials from which forms have been cut away.", "answer":0,"answers":["Stenciling"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A method of watercolor painting, but prepared with a more gluey base, producing a less transparent effect.", "answer":0,"answers":["Gouache"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement in American painting and sculpture that originated in the late 1950s. It emphasized pure, reduced forms and strict, systematic compositions.", "answer":0,"answers":["Minimalism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement in European painting in the seventeenth and early eighteenth centuries, characterized by violent movement, strong emotion, and dramatic lighting and coloring.", "answer":0,"answers":["Baroque"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement of the 1920s and 1930s that began in France. It explored the unconscious, often using images from dreams. It used spontaneous techniques and featured unexpected juxtapositions of objects.", "answer":0,"answers":["Surrealism"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement of the 1960s and 1970s that emphasized the artistic idea over the art object. It attempted to free art from the confines of the gallery and the pedestal.", "answer":0,"answers":["Conceptual art"],"source":""},
  {"category_id":"ART_AND_LITERATURE", "lang":"en", "tags":["ART_AND_LITERATURE"], "question":"A movement that began in Britain and the United States in the 1950s. It used the images and techniques of mass media, advertising, and popular culture, often in an ironic way.", "answer":0,"answers":["Pop art"],"source":""}
]